<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>AZ</title>
        <link>andrewzah.com</link>
        <description>Sometimes relevant thoughts by Andrew</description>
        <generator>Zola</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="andrewzah.com/tags/memorization/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Better Anki Usage Guide [2019]</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>andrewzah.com/posts/better-anki-usage-guide-2019/</link>
                <guid>andrewzah.com/posts/better-anki-usage-guide-2019/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;As you may or may not know, I love &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;apps.ankiweb.net&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Anki&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the spaced repetition flash cards app. I&#x27;ve been using it in my Korean learning journey for almost one and a half years now and I&#x27;ve written about it before. It&#x27;s a good app, but you can have a much better experience by making some modifications to it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don&#x27;t know what Anki is or why it&#x27;s compelling, I recommend you read &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;augmentingcognition.com&#x2F;ltm.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Augmenting Long-term Memory&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a blog post by Michael Nielsen. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;senrigan.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;everything-i-know-strategies-tips-and-tricks-for-spaced-repetition-anki&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Everything I know: Tips and Tricks for Anki&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by Jeff Shek also has a beginner&#x27;s guide.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#x27;re new to Anki, the very first thing I recommend doing is &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;apps.ankiweb.net&#x2F;docs&#x2F;manual.html&quot;&gt;reading the manual&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, or at least &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;apps.ankiweb.net&#x2F;docs&#x2F;manual.html#the-basics&quot;&gt;the basics&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend using Anki for at least 2-3 weeks before reading the rest of this article.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;changing-default-settings&quot;&gt;Changing default settings&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anki out of the box has two problematic defaults, and one default that I don&#x27;t recommend personally.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;resetting-card-progress&quot;&gt;Resetting card progress&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#x27;s say you have learned a card, but when you review it you make a mistake in recalling it, for whatever reason. Call it a brain fart, or pressing too quickly, etc. Or you simply forgot!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, Anki resets your progress to that of a new card. So even if you had worked the card up to a ~4 month interval, now you have to see it in  1 day, 2 days, 4 days, all over again...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you forget a card, you still had learned it at one point. Which means re-learning it is now significantly easier. By completely resetting the card&#x27;s intervals, Anki is wasting your time. It slowly conditions you to be unwilling to press &lt;code&gt;Again&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, which is not desireable at all.&lt;a id=&quot;footnote-cite-0&quot; href=&quot;#footnote-0&quot;&gt;(0)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: In your deck&#x27;s options group under Lapses, change &lt;code&gt;New interval&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;70%&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. This means if you forget a card, the new interval will be 70% of the old one. As for why I chose 70%, it just felt like an appropriate amount–feel free to play with different percentages to see what works best for you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;taking-too-long-to-mark-leeches&quot;&gt;Taking too long to mark Leeches&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you initially learn a card (the card reached  a 1 day interval in default anki), if you forget it 8 times, Anki marks it as a Leech and suspends the card, not showing it to you anymore.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A card being a leech generally means its too complicated, or you&#x27;re getting it confused with a similar one. 8 times means it&#x27;s going to take way too long to identify cards that are problematic.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: In your deck&#x27;s options group under Lapses, change &lt;code&gt;Leech threshold&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;4&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. You may also want to change &lt;code&gt;Leech action&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;tag only&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. This way you can easily sort for leech cards and modify or delete them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for handling leech cards, you generally want to simplify the card, or delete it outright. With the time and energy that you wasted on trying to recall a leech you could have learned a bunch of other cards. If it&#x27;s a word that you don&#x27;t want to delete, you can suspend the card, and practice using that word outside of anki. When you feel more comfortable with it you can unsuspend it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;mixing-new-and-review-cards&quot;&gt;Mixing new and review cards&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, Anki mixes new and review cards. However, reviewing is vastly more important than learning new cards–it&#x27;s okay if you don&#x27;t memorize new cards every day, but missing reviews really hurts your memorization progress.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By putting reviews first, you can always do reviews daily and then choose to learn new words or not depending on how busy you are, how tired you are, etc. If the cards are mixed you can&#x27;t do this, making it likely you&#x27;ll just skip Anki for that day entirely, which can can quickly snowball into not using anki at all anymore. This happened to me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: In Anki&#x27;s preferences, change &lt;code&gt;Mix new cards and reviews&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;Show new cards after reviews&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;making-better-card-templates&quot;&gt;Making better card templates&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Basic&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; card template in Anki has two fields: &lt;code&gt;Front&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Back&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. This is the minimum for flashcards obviously, but as you make cards it&#x27;s likely you&#x27;ll want to have separate information.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time my personal &lt;strong&gt;Zah Korean&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; card template has grown to eight fields: &lt;code&gt;english&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;korean&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;grammarType&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;samples&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;hanja&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;notes&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;image&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;sound&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. On the front I show &lt;code&gt;english&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;grammarType&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; as a hint. Some people put sample sentences but I find this leads to short-circuiting your recall; instead of recalling the word you recognize that sentence.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have a &lt;strong&gt;Zah Colorcard&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; template which has a &lt;code&gt;hexColor&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; field. Because I initially tried to learn colors in Korean like regular vocabulary, which makes no sense. Anki lets you pull in values easily in the template&#x27;s html and css sections.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can modify a card&#x27;s fields by going to Add or Edit, then clicking on &lt;code&gt;Fields...&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. You can add a new card type by going to Add or Edit, then click on the type, and then click &lt;code&gt;Manage&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;better-styling-with-html-and-css&quot;&gt;Better styling with html and css&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Default anki&#x27;s styling is very plain. I recommend modifying it to show different fields in different colors. For example, my &lt;code&gt;grammarType&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; field is rendered in green while &lt;code&gt;hanja&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; is rendered in purple. I render my color card&#x27;s hex value dynamically. Here&#x27;s what my cards look like; the horizontal line denotes the front and back:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;s3.amazonaws.com&amp;#x2F;andrewzah.com&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;017&amp;#x2F;templates.jpg&quot; data-lity data-lity-desc=&quot;How my templates look for sample cards&quot; alt=&quot;How my templates look for sample cards&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;full&quot; async-src=&quot;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;s3.amazonaws.com&amp;#x2F;andrewzah.com&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;017&amp;#x2F;templates.jpg&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can go to Browse, Add, or Edit and click on &lt;code&gt;Cards...&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; to get to the style dialogue. Some premade decks include nice styling for you, or default to a night mode. For more in-depth info, you can visit &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;apps.ankiweb.net&#x2F;docs&#x2F;manual.html#card-styling&quot;&gt;styling in the anki manual&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-behavior-changing-plugins-are-needed&quot;&gt;Why behavior-changing plugins are needed&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, the way Anki treats cards is not intuitive, and actually hampers your memorization progress. Let&#x27;s say you&#x27;re reviewing a card–you have four options. &lt;code&gt;Again&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, if you forget, and &lt;code&gt;Hard&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Good&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;Easy&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You would assume this means &amp;quot;I (the user) had a hard&#x2F;good&#x2F;easy time recalling this card today&amp;quot;, right? Well, Anki actually sees it as &amp;quot;this card is intrinsically more difficult; please modify it permanently&amp;quot;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huh?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see, every card in Anki has an individual &lt;code&gt;ease&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; percentage, starting at 250% by default. The algorithm that calculates a new interval goes like:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#ffffff;&quot;&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;color:#323232;&quot;&gt;NewInterval = OldInterval × CardEase × DeckIntervalModifier

Where:
  OldInterval: 1 day is the first default value
  CardEase: 250% by default
  DeckIntervalModifier: 1.0 by default, set on a per-deck basis
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you hit &lt;code&gt;Again&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Hard&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Easy&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, Anki modifies the ease by &lt;code&gt;-20%&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;-15%&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;+15%&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, respectively. A card&#x27;s ease can&#x27;t go lower than 130%. You can see now why people recommend not hitting &lt;code&gt;Easy&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; at all.. it quickly snowballs.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;smol-img&quot; async-src=&quot;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;s3.amazonaws.com&amp;#x2F;andrewzah.com&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;017&amp;#x2F;wack.jpg&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you might be saying, why is seeing cards too often, aka &amp;quot;overlearning&amp;quot;, an issue? Either way, I&#x27;m seeing more difficult cards more often.. Well, research suggests that after an initial period, the extra time spent doesn&#x27;t actually lead to better recall.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one study (Rohrer, Taylor, Pashler, Wixted, &amp;amp; Cepeda, 2005), college students learned novel vocabulary (e.g., cicatrix–scar), cycling through a list of word–definition pairs either 5 or 10 times. &lt;strong&gt;The extra 5 cycles yielded a substantial benefit after 1 week, but the gain was no longer apparent after 4 weeks&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; ... From a long-term perspective, overlearning appears to be inefficient almost to the point of wasting time.[0]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now take a look at what happens in Anki if you lower the ease too much:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;s3.amazonaws.com&amp;#x2F;andrewzah.com&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;017&amp;#x2F;ease-example.jpg&quot; data-lity data-lity-desc=&quot;An image showing how a cards ease affects its intervals&quot; alt=&quot;An image showing how a cards ease affects its intervals&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;full&quot; async-src=&quot;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;s3.amazonaws.com&amp;#x2F;andrewzah.com&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;017&amp;#x2F;ease-example.jpg&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;image-desc&quot;&gt; Image taken from Guide to Anki Intervals and Learning Steps[1] &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So even if you know a card enough to hit &lt;code&gt;Good&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, if you had hit &lt;code&gt;Hard&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; 3-4 times prior, the interval growth rate is permanently stunted due to how Anki works. You would have to hit &lt;code&gt;Easy&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; to balance it which is counterintuitive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research also suggests that larger spacing is better in the long term.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a 9-year longitudinal investigation, 4 subjects learned and relearned 300 English-foreign language word pairs. Either 13 or 26 relearning sessions were administered at intervals of 14, 28, or 56 days. Retention was tested for 1, 2, 3, or 5 years after training terminated. &lt;strong&gt;The longer intersession intervals slowed down acquisition slightly, but this disadvantage during training was offset hy substantially higher retention.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Thirteen retraining sessions spaced at 56 days yielded retention comparable to 26 sessions spaced at 14 days.[2]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our results can be summarized as follows. We find that over substantial time periods, spacing has powerful (and typically nonmonotonic) effects on retention, with optimal memory occurring when spacing is some modest fraction of the final retention interval (perhaps about 10%–20%).[1]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that out of the way, here are the plugins I use.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;utilizing-subdecks&quot;&gt;Utilizing subdecks&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you review from multiple decks daily, you can use a parent deck with subdecks to mix reviews. This is my own personal opinion, but I think it&#x27;s better for recall if you change contexts. This is more like recall in real life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making subdecks in anki is really easy–just make a parent deck, and drag decks onto it. Or you can manually rename the deck in this format: &lt;code&gt;Parent Deck Name::Subdeck Name&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. If done right, it should appear like this:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;s3.amazonaws.com&amp;#x2F;andrewzah.com&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;017&amp;#x2F;subdecks.png&quot; data-lity data-lity-desc=&quot;A picture of anki open displaying how the interface shows subdecks&quot; alt=&quot;A picture of anki open displaying how the interface shows subdecks&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;full&quot; async-src=&quot;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;s3.amazonaws.com&amp;#x2F;andrewzah.com&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;017&amp;#x2F;subdecks.png&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only issue is Anki will still do reviews one deck at a time. I tried using the experimental V2 scheduler, but it didn&#x27;t work for me. So now we have to turn to a plugin: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ankiweb.net&#x2F;shared&#x2F;info&#x2F;1460733408&quot;&gt;HoochieMama: Randomize Rev Queue&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. After you install this, open Anki&#x27;s preferences, and in the Muffins tab enable &lt;code&gt;Hoochie Mama! RandRevQ w&#x2F; subdeck limit&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: back up your anki before adding behavior modification plugins like this.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#x27;s it! Now you can review from multiple subdecks, and new cards are still deck by deck. If you want to mix new cards as well, there&#x27;s &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ankiweb.net&#x2F;shared&#x2F;info&#x2F;1173108619&quot;&gt;Hoochie Papa&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I personally don&#x27;t think that is as useful.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;utilizing-filter-decks&quot;&gt;Utilizing filter decks&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;visual-plugins&quot;&gt;Visual Plugins&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These aren&#x27;t really necessary but I like seeing stats. Give me all the stats.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;true-retention-by-card-maturity&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ankiweb.net&#x2F;shared&#x2F;info&#x2F;923360400&quot;&gt;True Retention by Card Maturity&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is basically a fancy stats plugin. You can see a detailed breakdown by day, week, and month, and see your true retention rate. You want roughly 80-90% retention. [TODO]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;more-decks-stats-and-time-left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ankiweb.net&#x2F;shared&#x2F;info&#x2F;1556734708&quot;&gt;More decks stats and time left&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;This addon shows extra information of the due cards and returns the expected time to finalize (Due+New).&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;enhance-main-window&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ankiweb.net&#x2F;shared&#x2F;info&#x2F;877182321&quot;&gt;Enhance main window&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This adds more stats to the main window via columns. As you can see in that link, the default config adds quite a lot, so I &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;gist.github.com&#x2F;azah&#x2F;0391ce0fc3e90f3defea75ef518fd195&quot;&gt;modified my config&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to pare it down, which looks like this:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;s3.amazonaws.com&amp;#x2F;andrewzah.com&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;017&amp;#x2F;enhanced.png&quot; data-lity data-lity-desc=&quot;A picture displaying how the anki main window looks different with this plugin enabled&quot; alt=&quot;A picture displaying how the anki main window looks different with this plugin enabled&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;full&quot; async-src=&quot;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;s3.amazonaws.com&amp;#x2F;andrewzah.com&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;017&amp;#x2F;enhanced.png&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that the stats at the bottom are from the &lt;code&gt;More decks stats and time left&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; plugin.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;progress-graphs-and-stats-for-mature-and-learned-cards&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ankiweb.net&#x2F;shared&#x2F;info&#x2F;266436365&quot;&gt;Progress graphs and stats for mature and learned cards&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adds two new graphs to the stats window.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;button-colours-good-again&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ankiweb.net&#x2F;shared&#x2F;info&#x2F;2494384865&quot;&gt;Button Colours (Good, Again)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply colorizes Again to be red, Good to be green, etc. It&#x27;s a small but nice thing to have when reviewing. There&#x27;s also &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ankiweb.net&#x2F;shared&#x2F;info&#x2F;1829090218&quot;&gt;Large and Colorful Buttons&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; if you wanted even more colorful buttons.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;kanji-grid&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ankiweb.net&#x2F;shared&#x2F;info&#x2F;909972618&quot;&gt;Kanji Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an awesome plugin that visually shows your kanji learning progress. Simply select a deck that has a &lt;code&gt;kanji&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; field, and run Tools &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Generate Kanji Grid&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. It looks like this:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;s3.amazonaws.com&amp;#x2F;andrewzah.com&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;017&amp;#x2F;kanji-grid.png&quot; data-lity data-lity-desc=&quot;A grid showing kanji characters with a color background based on how long the current interval is&quot; alt=&quot;A grid showing kanji characters with a color background based on how long the current interval is&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;full&quot; async-src=&quot;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;s3.amazonaws.com&amp;#x2F;andrewzah.com&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;017&amp;#x2F;kanji-grid.png&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was generated from my deck with the default settings.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;behavior-plugins&quot;&gt;Behavior Plugins&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where things get fun. These plugins change the core functionality of Anki, so please, read about them and make sure you understand what they do before adding them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Back up your Anki before installing these&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;search-in-add-card-dialogue&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ankiweb.net&#x2F;shared&#x2F;info&#x2F;1781298089&quot;&gt;Search in Add Card Dialogue&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This adds a pane to the &lt;code&gt;Add Card&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; window, letting you quickly search through your Anki decks for keywords. It&#x27;s very useful for finding duplicates, or searching among sample sentences.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only con is the search doesn&#x27;t work for non-ascii text. When I have time I plan on fixing this.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;resetez&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;massimmersionapproach.com&#x2F;table-of-contents&#x2F;anki&#x2F;low-key-anki&#x2F;low-key-anki-summary-and-installation&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ResetEZ&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This adds a command in your Tools menu called &lt;code&gt;Reset Ease + Force Sync After&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. It resets &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Anki cards to have the default ease value, 250%. You have to install it manually.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;no-penalties-or-boosting&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;massimmersionapproach.com&#x2F;table-of-contents&#x2F;anki&#x2F;low-key-anki&#x2F;low-key-anki-summary-and-installation&#x2F;&quot;&gt;No Penalties or Boosting&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This changes &lt;code&gt;Again&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Hard&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Easy&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; to not change the card&#x27;s ease value. By default, Anki modifies it by -20%, -15%, or +15%, respectively. This is a bad idea, and I go into more detail [in my other anki post][TODO]. This goes hand in hand with ResetEZ. It also needs to be manually installed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;hoochie-mama-randomize-rev-queue&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ankiweb.net&#x2F;shared&#x2F;info&#x2F;1460733408&quot;&gt;Hoochie Mama: Randomize Rev Queue&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;andrewzah.com&#x2F;posts&#x2F;better-anki-usage-guide-2019&#x2F;#utilizing-subdecks&quot;&gt;Making use of subdecks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; above. This randomizes review cards in subdecks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;other-plugins&quot;&gt;Other Plugins&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There may be plugins for the language that you&#x27;re learning. Japanese has several, for example. It&#x27;s worth searching &amp;quot;anki {language}&amp;quot; to see what&#x27;s available.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering that we end up using Anki for years, it&#x27;s worth taking some time to improve it and read the documentation closely. Is there a plugin or change that you feel like I missed? Let me know.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also written a post on &lt;a href=&quot;..&#x2F;posts&#x2F;things-to-avoid-with-anki&quot;&gt;general things to avoid while using Anki&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that I recommend you check out.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Things to avoid with Anki</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>andrewzah.com/posts/things-to-avoid-with-anki/</link>
                <guid>andrewzah.com/posts/things-to-avoid-with-anki/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;For those unaware, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;apps.ankiweb.net&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Anki&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a free app that implements [active recall] with &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Spaced_repetition&quot;&gt;spaced repetition&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. If you&#x27;re new to Anki, the very first thing I recommend doing is &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;apps.ankiweb.net&#x2F;docs&#x2F;manual.html&quot;&gt;reading the manual&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, or at least &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;apps.ankiweb.net&#x2F;docs&#x2F;manual.html#the-basics&quot;&gt;the basics&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some common mistakes people make when getting into flash cards and spaced repetition for the first time, as well as Anki. Considering that Anki is generally used for years, correcting bad habits pays large dividends in the long run.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So with that said, let&#x27;s get into it!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;not-doing-anki-daily&quot;&gt;Not doing Anki daily&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you take away only one tip from this post, let it be this one. Nothing else here matters if you don&#x27;t consistently review cards daily.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire point of Anki is spaced repetition. Every time you skip a day&#x27;s reviews, the following session will become more difficult. For non-mature words (less than 30 day intervals) it&#x27;s crucial that you review. If you don&#x27;t review for a long time, you will soon have hundreds of reviews stacked up, which is super demotivating.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to do Anki before bed, but this sometimes led to me skipping it due to work, friends, or life just taking up more time and energy than expected. Now I consistently do anki either in the morning after I&#x27;ve fully woken up, or around lunch.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you change your study time, make sure to update your Anki Preferences, under Basic &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Next day starts at&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. This tip goes hand in hand with the next one.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;mixing-reviews-and-new-words&quot;&gt;Mixing reviews and new words&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is Anki&#x27;s default behavior. I personally recommend against this as sometimes you don&#x27;t have the time or energy in a day to sit down and learn the new cards. It&#x27;s okay if you don&#x27;t learn new words, but missing reviews is really bad.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you can&#x27;t only do the reviews, since they&#x27;re mixed in with the new cards! So guess what ends up happening? Both the reviews and new cards get skipped...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By changing Anki preferences to &lt;code&gt;Show new cards after reviews&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, you can always do reviews without worry. After you wake up, while you commute, et cetera.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;studying-too-many-new-words&quot;&gt;Studying too many new words&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not go over 20 words&#x2F;day unless you are studying at least 1-2 hours every day. Initially it may be doable but reviews will pile up so fast it&#x27;s scary.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do 20 words a day, every day, for a year, you will learn 6,720 words. That is pretty darn good! For most, if not all, languages, 3-5k words will let you have basic conversations.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;having-the-foreign-word-on-the-front-side&quot;&gt;Having the foreign word on the front side&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#x27;re using Anki to learn a foreign language, you want to speak that language with someone, right? Think about how a conversation goes as a beginner.  First, you think of the word &lt;em&gt;in your native language&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, then you think of the equivalent foreign word.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you put a foreign word on the front of your anki cards, then you&#x27;re doing it totally backward! That just trains you to recognize a foreign word when you see it; it doesn&#x27;t train you to remember a foreign word from your native word.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also make automatically make cards that go both ways if you use the &lt;code&gt;Basic (and reversed card)&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; template. So adding a card with [dog, 강아지] will make another card that&#x27;s [강아지, dog]. If you only want -some- cards to have a reverse, you can use the provided &lt;code&gt;Basic (optional reversed card)&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; template. This one only makes a reverse if you put something in the &lt;code&gt;Add Reverse&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; field (it can be any input, it doesn&#x27;t show anywhere).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;apps.ankiweb.net&#x2F;docs&#x2F;manual.html#reverse-cards&quot;&gt;the manual&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for more information on reverse cards.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;only-using-premade-decks&quot;&gt;Only using premade decks&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#x27;re a beginner to studying a language, using a premade deck is fine due to the sheer amount of time it takes to add words to a deck. However the longer you study, the more you need your own personal deck.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you use someone else&#x27;s deck, it&#x27;s basically a random collection of words that you lack the context for. For your own personal deck you have to see the word somewhere first, giving you more of a feeling for the context.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#x27;re trying to mass-memorize words (say, for a language test), I recommend using Anki&#x27;s &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;apps.ankiweb.net&#x2F;docs&#x2F;manual.html#decks&quot;&gt;parent&#x2F;subdecks feature&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. That way you can use a premade deck &lt;em&gt;and&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; your personal deck at the same time. Spiffy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I explain subdecks a bit more in my &lt;a href=&quot;..&#x2F;better-anki-usage-guide-2019#utilizing-subdecks&quot;&gt;Better Anki Usage&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; post.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;not-including-sample-sentences&quot;&gt;Not including sample sentences&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of language learning decks just have the word and its translation. For very basic words this can be fine, but for most words you really do need sample sentences so you can see the context as well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I include 3 sample sentences in all the cards I make, as well as notes, common word pairings, and the grammar type.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;having-too-many-concepts-per-card&quot;&gt;Having too many concepts per card&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good anki card should have one concept. Avoid memorizing lists if you really have to. If you do have to memorize a list, turn it into an enumeration (1. 2. 3...). If you have multiple concepts, make multiple cards.&lt;a id=&quot;refer-0&quot; href=&quot;#reference-0&quot;&gt;[0]&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When memorizing foreign words it&#x27;s really tempting to put every definition into one card. Don&#x27;t do this. Putting related definitions together is fine, but if a word has multiple different meanings, it needs different cards.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see this a lot in premade decks, with 1 card having 4 or 5 totally unrelated usages of a word–and no sentence samples either, of course.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;pressing-easy-too-easily&quot;&gt;Pressing &#x27;easy&#x27; too easily&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s can be tempting to give a review card the &#x27;Easy&#x27; grade, quickly giving it large intervals. Don&#x27;t do this unless you know the word quite well (in which case, why even have the card at all?). Otherwise the interval will increase rapidly, and you&#x27;ll have forgotten it by then.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, due to how Anki works, pressing &lt;code&gt;Easy&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; (or &lt;code&gt;Hard&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;) &lt;em&gt;permanently&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; modifies that card, giving it way longer intervals than what it should be. I go over this in detail in my &lt;a href=&quot;..&#x2F;better-anki-usage-guide-2019#why-behavior-changing-plugins-are-needed&quot;&gt;Better Anki Usage&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; post. Almost all long-term Anki users that I talk to do not press &lt;code&gt;Easy&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; often, or ever.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;not-syncing-all-the-time&quot;&gt;Not syncing all the time&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should always sync after every session, especially if you edit anything.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know &lt;code&gt;y&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; is the sync shortcut?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;not-memorizing-keyboard-shortcuts&quot;&gt;Not memorizing keyboard shortcuts&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, learning a few shortcuts is useful since Anki is used so much.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When reviewing a card:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;undo -&amp;gt; ctrl&#x2F;cmd-z&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spacebar =&amp;gt; Flip the card&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1,2,3,4 =&amp;gt; The numbers follow the order of the grading buttons. So for a review, which has &lt;code&gt;Again&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Hard&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Good&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Easy&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, those are 1,2,3,4 respectively. A new card has &lt;code&gt;Again&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Good&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Easy&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; by default, which are 1, 2, 3.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e =&amp;gt; edit card&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other shortcuts:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;r =&amp;gt; replay audio&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@ =&amp;gt; suspend a card&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;m =&amp;gt; mark a card (adds a &lt;code&gt;marked&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; tag so you can find it easily later)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ctrl or cmd-1,2,3,4 =&amp;gt; flag a card with red, orange, green, or blue, respectively&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;- =&amp;gt; bury a card (hide it until tomorrow)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Window&#x2F;tool shortcuts:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;y =&amp;gt; sync&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;d =&amp;gt; go to decks overview&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b =&amp;gt; browse cards&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a =&amp;gt; add card&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;t =&amp;gt; stats&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&#x2F; =&amp;gt; custom study session&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f =&amp;gt; create filter deck&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overkill, you say? Well.. yeah, probably. Aside from spacebar, 1,2,3,4, r, and y, you don&#x27;t really need to know the rest unless you like being super duper efficient.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some of the problems I&#x27;ve encountered while using Anki. Are there other ones you think I should talk about? Let me know.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#x27;re interested in Anki, I recommend reading my &lt;a href=&quot;..&#x2F;posts&#x2F;better-anki-usage-guide-2019&quot;&gt;Better Anki Usage&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; post to fix some of Anki&#x27;s wonky defaults and unintuitive behavior.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
