<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>AZ</title>
        <link>andrewzah.com</link>
        <description>Sometimes relevant thoughts by Andrew</description>
        <generator>Zola</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="andrewzah.com/categories/general/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Korean for Programmers</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>andrewzah.com/posts/korean-for-programmers/</link>
                <guid>andrewzah.com/posts/korean-for-programmers/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I was inspired to write this after reading &lt;em&gt;German for Programmers&lt;&#x2f;em&gt;.&lt;a id=&quot;refer-0&quot; href=&quot;#reference-0&quot;&gt;[0]&lt;&#x2f;a&gt; It&#x27;s quite likely that I&#x27;m just biased to see things a certain way because I work with programming languages for a living, but I often find myself drawing comparisons among Korean and programming.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>My growth as a self-taught developer in 2018</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>andrewzah.com/posts/my-growth-self-taught-software-developer-in-2018/</link>
                <guid>andrewzah.com/posts/my-growth-self-taught-software-developer-in-2018/</guid>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that 2019 is almost here, I&#x27;ve been reflecting on my personal &amp;amp; professional journey as a self taught programmer so far.
Here&#x27;s my story of going from a media arts degree and no job to working fulltime remotely.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Finishing that Marathon</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>andrewzah.com/posts/finishing-that-marathon/</link>
                <guid>andrewzah.com/posts/finishing-that-marathon/</guid>
                <description>&lt;ol start=&quot;17&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I realized today that it has been 17 months since I first started learning Korean. 17 months ago, I flew to Korea and lived there for about 8 months. Then I came back to the US 9 months ago. I&#x27;d like to say my Korean ability reflects 17 months, but it does not. This has to do with &lt;code&gt;motivation&lt;&#x2f;code&gt;, or my occasional lack thereof.&lt;&#x2f;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2f;ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-s-easy-to-start-off-strong&quot;&gt;It&#x27;s easy to start off strong&lt;&#x2f;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beginning of anything, especially learning a language, is always the easiest part. You go from nothing to something. With languages, you go from not knowing anything to knowing a few things in that domain- an infinite% improvement!! And afterwards your ability will continue to skyrocket- relatively speaking.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For real languages this amounts to learning the alphabet or script, and some very basic words or phrases. Then more words and some beginner grammar. For programming languages, it&#x27;s the code syntax and style, then the surrounding ecosystem, etcetera. You can keep this up for a while, months, even a year if you&#x27;re lucky. There are many things to learn but they&#x27;re still fresh, exciting, new.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along this journey, people start to fall off for various reasons, but there are two big ones. First, the law of diminishing returns. You go from infinite! increase, to 100% increase, to 10% increase, until it becomes more of a steady drip.  Second, in the beginning of any field, study, or profession, you cannot know how little you actually know. How little ability you actually have. Don&#x27;t worry, you will realize this once you start to become more intermediate, after longer exposure—maybe 3-4 months, maybe a year. For languages, this is typically when it becomes frustrating. You&#x27;re no longer impressed by &amp;quot;Hi, my name is Andrew&amp;quot;-style basic speech... You&#x27;re yearning for you know, actual conversations.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet you can&#x27;t.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, you know that you &lt;em&gt;have&lt;&#x2f;em&gt; to study way more in order to reach that level. This is vexing—since we don&#x27;t tend to look at things from a relative standpoint. As improvement comes day by day it&#x27;s tough to realize just how much we&#x27;ve improved! You can&#x27;t do advanced things yet &lt;em&gt;but that&#x27;s okay&lt;&#x2f;em&gt;. That&#x27;s why we separate intermediate and advanced, I suppose. So at this point, you either become dejected and eventually stop, or you have a new fire lit under you, pushing you forward even harder.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;s3.amazonaws.com&amp;#x2f;andrewzah.com&amp;#x2f;posts&amp;#x2f;005&amp;#x2f;lawofdimin.png&quot; data-lity data-lity-desc=&quot;Graphic demonstrating the Law of Diminishing Returns&quot; alt=&quot;Graphic demonstrating the Law of Diminishing Returns&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;full&quot; async-src=&quot;https:&amp;#x2f;&amp;#x2f;s3.amazonaws.com&amp;#x2f;andrewzah.com&amp;#x2f;posts&amp;#x2f;005&amp;#x2f;lawofdimin.png&quot;&#x2f;&gt;
&lt;&#x2f;a&gt;&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;keepin-on-is-astoundingly-difficult&quot;&gt;Keepin&#x27; on is astoundingly difficult&lt;&#x2f;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you get past the hurdle of keeping on despite realizing how little you actually know, it just becomes similar to &lt;code&gt;work&lt;&#x2f;code&gt;. I say similar, because you&#x27;re still &lt;em&gt;studying&lt;&#x2f;em&gt;. You&#x27;re NOT just showing up- that&#x27;s useless. But you ARE still doing critical analysis, reflecting, and growing.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You just have to wake up, every day, and keep at it. Endlessly. At this point you really need to have the fires of passion burning, to sustain this.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#x27;ll still find enjoyment in the studying, certainly, why else would you be doing this? Yet it just isn&#x27;t quite as exhilarating as the beginning. There aren&#x27;t much more large improvements- just little things here and there that add up to you becoming a proper professional, a superior-level language speaker, and so on.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These little nuggets can be fascinating in their own right too. For example, I&#x27;ve been using &lt;code&gt;git&lt;&#x2f;code&gt; for about ~3.5 years now? And I &lt;em&gt;just&lt;&#x2f;em&gt; learned about &lt;code&gt;git commit -v&lt;&#x2f;code&gt;. It&#x27;s a small thing but it makes writing &lt;code&gt;git commit&lt;&#x2f;code&gt; messages much easier. Find a way to derive enjoyment fom discovering little things like this.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;staying-motivated&quot;&gt;Staying motivated&lt;&#x2f;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can study something an insane number of hours. Let&#x27;s see you keep it up for a week, a month, a year, 10 years. Here are some things that helped me retain my passion in studying Korean and programming:&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taking breaks occasionally&lt;&#x2f;strong&gt;. If I only had one recommendation, this would be it. There&#x27;s just something about taking a week or longer break to clear your mind. Every single time I have done this, it only made me want to study Korean or programming anymore- I had missed it! Yet the time off allowed my mind to relax and ponder, giving me a fresh perspective.&lt;&#x2f;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finding and creating a circle of friends who also study what you study. When you learn new things, you have a responsive group to share them with! When you have questions, you have people to turn to. Properly done, a circle of friends will keep you quite interested and motivated. This is why the &lt;em&gt;Super Smash Bros.&lt;&#x2f;em&gt; tournament scene continues to live. It&#x27;s hard to quit something when everyone you know does it.&lt;&#x2f;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changing up the mediums you study. Do you usually watch foreign tv shows to study? Try reading a short book or a comic. This one is more for language learners.&lt;&#x2f;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exploring different cultural things. My interest in Korean basically doubled when I started watching Korean TV shows like 아는 형님 and 런닝맨. Depending on the show you can learn a lot about the country&#x27;s culture and history.&lt;&#x2f;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reflecting on your progress from say, a year ago. Look at your notes if possible, etc. This goes with what I said above about really putting things in perspective.&lt;&#x2f;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attending a language exchange or going somewhere that forces you to use the language. Personally I find language exchanges slightly forced&#x2f;awkward sometimes, but they can be good too. When I visit Korea again, I&#x27;ll be attending 문화원s (cultural centers that offer classes on traditional Korean arts—in Korean only).&lt;&#x2f;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teaching people who are less skilled than yourself. &lt;em&gt;You don&#x27;t have to be a master to be a teacher&lt;&#x2f;em&gt;. I personally believe teaching is one of the best ways of retaining information. Wait until you&#x27;re mid-intermediate&#x2f;advanced though, unless it&#x27;s very basic teaching. The last thing you want is to teach someone incorrect things.&lt;&#x2f;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2f;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;&#x2f;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some of the lessons I learned over time. When I moved back to the US, my motivation was killed for a while because I didn&#x27;t explore other avenues like tv shows. I did study, but maybe once a week. Which was useless. I began improving again when I properly sat down, figured out my goals, and began studying every. single. day.&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I can say is Keep on keepin&#x27; on. Be honest with yourself and make sure you really want it- then dedicate yourself. Figure out reasonable, attainable goals, not perfectionist ones. Learning anything well is &lt;em&gt;never&lt;&#x2f;em&gt; a sprint—it&#x27;s a marathon. Eventually you will be amazing at it, but only if you practice correctly and analyze yourself. Just showing up is not enough!!&lt;&#x2f;p&gt;
</description>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
